Guide to the Stanford University, Hospital, Monthly Reports
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Hospital, monthly reports
1914-1940
SC0042
Stanford University. Hospital.
3 Linear feet
In addition to a census of patients, these typescript reports cover the nursing school, medical supplies, dietary kitchens, operating room, housekeeping, engineering services, clinics, social service department, and medical departments such as obstetrics, anesthesiology, radiology, and physical therapy. Most of the information is statistical, with some financial information. In some years, the social services reports and the nursing school reports included a narrative account.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
At the time of these reports the Stanford University Hospital (also known as Lane Hospital) was located in San Francisco.
Description of the Collection
In addition to a census of patients, these typescript reports cover the nursing school, medical supplies, dietary kitchens, operating room, housekeeping, engineering services, clinics, social service department, and medical departments such as obstetrics, anesthesiology, radiology, and physical therapy. Most of the information is statistical, with some financial information. In some years, the social services reports and the nursing school reports included a narrative account.
Access Terms
Lane Hospital (San Francisco, Calif.).; Stanford University. Hospital.; Stanford University. School of Nursing.; Hospitals, University.; Medical care --California --San Francisco.
Collection Contents
- Monthy Reports
  - Lane Hospital
    - Aug.-Oct., 1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Nov. 1914-Feb. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Mar.-June 1915 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - July-Sept. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1915 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Jan.-March 1916 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - April-June 1916 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - June-July 1916 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Aug.-Oct. 1916 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Nov.-Dec. 1916 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Jan.-March 1917 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - April-June 1917 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - July-Sept. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1917 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Jan.-Feb. 1918 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - March-April 1918 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - May-June 1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - July-Sept. 1918 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Oct.-Nov. 1918 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 1918-Feb. 1919 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - March-April 1919 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - May-June 1919 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - July-Aug. 1919 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Sept.-Oct. 1919 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Nov.-Dec. 1919 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Jan.-March 1920 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - April-June 1920 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - July-Sept. 1920 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1920 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Jan.-March 1921 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - April-June 1921 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - July-Aug. 1921 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Sept.-Nov. 1921 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Dec. 1921-March 1922 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - April-June 1922 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - July-Sept. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1922 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Jan.-April 1923 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - May-July 1923 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1923 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Jan.-March 1924 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - April-June 1924 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - July-Sept. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Oct.-Dec. 1924 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Jan.-March 1925 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - April-June 1925 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - July-Aug. 1925 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1925 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Jan.-April 1926 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - May-July 1926 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Aug.-Nov. 1926 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Dec. 1926-Feb. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - March-May 1927 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - June-Aug. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1927 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Jan.-April 1928 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - May-July 1928 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Aug.-Nov. 1928 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Dec. 1928-Feb. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - March-May 1929 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - June-Aug. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sept.-Oct. 1929 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Dec. 1929-March 1930 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - April-Aug. 1930 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Sept. 1930-Jan. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Stanford University Hospital
    - March-April 1931 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - May-Sept. 1931 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Oct. 1931-Feb. 1932 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - March-July 1932 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1932 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Jan.-May 1933 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - June-Nov. 1933 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Dec. 1933-Feb. 1934 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - March-Aug. 1934 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1934 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Jan.-April 1935 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - May-July 1935 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Aug.-Dec. 1935 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Jan.-June 1936 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - July-Dec. 1936 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Jan.-April 1937 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - May-Aug. 1937 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1937 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Jan.-April 1938 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - May-Aug. 1938 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1938 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Jan.-April 1939 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - May-Aug. 1939 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Sept.-Dec. 1939 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Jan.-April 1940 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - May-Aug. 1940 (Box 6, Folder 19)